#### **Full Stack Developer**

renegrooth@gmail.com 0211802090

Auckland, New Zealand

# Rene Groothuis

### **Profile**

After working as an Electrician for 7 years on an expansive range of projects, I wanted to develop my problem-solving analytical and creative skills further. In order to improve on these skills I learnt as an electrician I have undertaken additional training and to refocus my skills towards Software Development.

I enjoyed the programming / problem solving side of being an Electrician. Working with Programmable Logic Controllers (PLC's) got me really intrigued in how software works and how much it helps people, so I committed to Software Devlopment by attending Dev Academy Aotearoa. In my new career I hope to continue solving complex problems with creativity and collaboration.

# **Experience**

# Apprentice Software Developer at Dev Academy Aotearoa, Auckland

01/2023-05/2023

- This was a life-changing 17-week full-immersion software development bootcamp that closely represents working in a modern development team. The course taught me a modern development stack.
- Over these weeks I learnt JavaScript, Typescript, React, Redux, SQlite3 with knex, Node.js, Express.js.
- We worked in pairs, groups and solo to work on improving our technical skills and human skills to complete projects and assingments.
- During the course we had to work on our own personal projects which
  we presented, I made an application for electricians to easily fill out
  neccessary code of compliance paperwork, I made this not only to
  increase my skills but to also make a simpler solution for people
  working in trades.

#### **Electrician at Prolectrics, Auckland**

#### 11/2018-12/2022

- Design and build Programmable Logic Controllers (PLC) systems for molding machines, saftey systems, lighting systems, pump systems and marine systems.
- Skills using Allen-bradley, Omron, Pilz and Sick software to control the systems mentioned above.
- Worked well independently and in a team to solve problems, working on multipule different projects that required a wide range of knowledge and organisation.
- Served as a friendly, hardworking, and punctual employee.

### Links

<u>GitHub</u>

<u>LinkedIn</u>

Personal Website

#### **Skills**

**Typescript** 

React

Redux

Node.js

SQlite3

Ability to Work in a Team

Computer Skills

**Electrical Wiring** 

Troubleshooting

Safe Work Practices

# **Hobbies**

In my spare time I enjoy running, going to the gym, football and skiing in winter

## References

References available upon request

- Organised and prioritized work to complete assignments in a timely, efficient manner.
- Remained committed to adding to my knowledge and skills base, keeping up with the latest trends in the electrical space.
- Designed, planed, and executed new installs and regular maintenance for a wide range of customers.
- Work along side factorys to maintain, diagnose and repair machines, including upgrading safety systems, installing new circuits and testing and repairing emergency systems.

#### Electrician Apprentice at ETCO, Auckland

08/2016-11/2018

Did my apprenticeship training through ETCO where we worked with different companies to learn a wide range of electrical skills. Including residential, commercial and industrial.

### **Education**

Level 6 Applied Technology of Software

Development, Dev Academy Aotearoa, Auckland

01/2023-05/2023

An intensive 17-week web development training program that replicates real industry work with a focus on technical and non-technical skills.

#### Level 4 Electrical Engineering, ETCO, Auckland

01/2017-11/2019

New Zealand Certificate in Electrical Engineering Theory and Practice (Trade) (Level 4).